# HENRY S. NAVARRO

104 W Brilloso Ln, Mountain House, CA 95391 USA +1 510 378 2435 | henrysnavarro@icloud.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer, UX Designer and Technical Leader with 20+ years of experience. Main proficiency in Web Front-end and capability for full-stack. Hands-on skills in Product Design, Product Management and Project Management. Background in Physics, Computer Engineering, Human-Computer Interaction and Multimedia. Effective contributor in both team and individual settings. Keen sense of product accuracy and best practices. Life-long dedication to constant improvement and re-invention.

# **SKILLS**

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, NodeJS, BackboneJS, jQuery, ReactJS, Polymer, Web Components, Bower, Git, Flash, Flex, ActionScript, SQL, NoSQL, UNIX Shell Scripts, CloudFoundry, Google Cloud Platform, Jenkins CI/CD, Chrome Developer Tools, Firebug, Java

Single-Page Applications, Micro-Services, Agile (Scrum), Behavior/Test-Driven Development, Design Thinking, UX Design, Rapid Prototyping, Build Automation, Information Architecture, Application Security, Threat Modeling, Data Visualization, Technical Documentation, Technology Evaluation, Experiment Design, Product Market Research.

# INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Designed and implemented software products in the following industries:

- User Interface Libraries
- Online Banking
- Renewable Energy
- Healthcare
- E-Learning

- Online Video and Advertising
- Industrial Internet of Things (IIOT)
- Bioinformatics
- Manufacturing

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### SENIOR DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST, GE DIGITAL, NOV 2015-MAY 2018

- Developed starter applications, authored learning guides and coordinated with training team for accelerating developer on-boarding and adoption of our products.
- Designed and implemented interactive diagrams that convey IIOT value proposition, helping achieve high customer interest in GE's Minds+Machines annual event
- Designed, developed and enhanced re-usable web components used in multiple applications for company's solution portfolio
- Created infographics and diagrams that effectively convey how company's solutions worked
- Facilitated developer adoption through code samples, forum responses, and direct technical assistance
- Consistently performed beyond annual goals

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GE HEALTHCARE, AUG 2014 - NOV 2015

- Designed and implemented web applications modules and UI components for GE's Centricity 360, its main cloud-based healthcare solution offering
- Designed and coded modules that became standard for frontend security layer in web applications
- Occupied role as main UX resource for engineering team, effectively managing issues at the intersection of design and technology
- Performed beyond annual goals

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ABB - POWER ONE, SEP 2012 - JUL 2014

- Enhanced web application frontend of company's main product offering for managing solar panel arrays
- Created interactive prototypes of user interface components for next generation of company's main web application offering
- Occupied role as main UX resource for entire engineering team, created icon sets, provided design opinions

### SENIOR UI DEVELOPER, SERENA SOFTWARE, NOV 2010 - APR 2012

Developed and maintained web application front-end, consulted with designers and product managers, testers and technical writers. Designed and maintained iconography for company's main software product. I was considered as the main resource for usability and user experience in the projects I participated in.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GLOBALENGLISH, SEP 2009 - APR 2010

Developed and maintained rich internet applications. Consulted with product designers, UX designers, product management and quality assurance. Improved asset development and deployment with the use of better software tools and identification of process inefficiencies and corresponding fixes.

# SENIOR WEB APPLICATIONS ENGINEER, CBS, APR 2008 - SEP 2009

Developed and maintained rich internet applications. Consulted with product designers, UX designers, product management and quality assurance. Developed code modules for integrating company's software with partner advertising content. Worked with company partners and external customers on technical details software integration. Led the architecture and development of the company's first robust online video streaming client software.

\*\*\* Additional employment history details available upon request \*\*\*

# **EDUCATION**

IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY – GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN HCI, 2012

CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY – SUBJECTS IN MBA, 2005

U.C. SANTA CRUZ EXTENSION – CERTIFICATE IN COMPUTER NETWORKS, 1999

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY, BACHELORS IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 1992

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY, BACHELORS IN PHYSICS, 1991

# TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Predix Developer, Predix Architect, 2017-2018

Agile Scrum Master and Product Owner, Scrum Alliance, 2015 - 2016

Building Essential Leadership Skills, General Electric, 2015

# PROFILE / PORTFOLIO

hifromhenry.carbonmade.com
www.linkedin.com/in/henrynavarro
www.github.com/henrysnavarro
www.github.com/gedesigntech